<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AceLewis.com</title>
    <description>A website for me to do things with</description>
    <link>https://acelewis.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://acelewis.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 22:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 22:10:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Alternatives to Ads and Why They Wouldn&#39;t Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a blog post on &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The Ethics of Adblock”&lt;/a&gt; stating that online Advertisements are a necessity to have free content however in this post I will explore the alternatives and explain my thoughts on why they will not work to monetize content on many websites.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people justify the use of Adblock my stating that it is an outdated business model and that websites should use other models to monetize their content, although other monetization techniques exist and can be used some websites they are not viable for most internet content. Here are a few of the biggest ideas to have an advertisement free internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-extra-fee&quot;&gt;The Extra Fee&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have heard from many people that an add free internet by having an extra fee to your ISP you pay on top of your usual internet, this may make sense at first as you already pay for a connection to the internet so you could just pay some more to remove the ads and then content creators also get paid by your extra fee, however it would never work. Firstly what should people be paid for? Page views? Content? Percentage of data traffic? Watch time? and how will your ISP know how much to give each person / company. Would your ISP have to track every website you visit (that’s if they don’t already) if so how would they know the origin of the traffic? Websites can be embedded on webpages in iFrames without you knowing and you can load that website. Not to mention how your ISP is going to pay everyone around the world. Every company, blog, from big to small would try to fight over who gets a cut and how much of a cut they should get, and to add to that you have to trust your ISP to hand out the money at all and not take bribes to give some people bigger cuts. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/news/11047801/Would-you-pay-140-a-year-for-an-ad-free-web.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Also it is expected that an internet user in the UK generate £140 in ad revenue a year&lt;/a&gt; so the fee would have to be over £10 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;crowd-sourcetip-jar&quot;&gt;Crowd Source/Tip Jar&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One method that is a little more viable than the “Extra Fee” method is the use of crowd sourcing and electronic tip jars. Crowd sourcing is becoming more common on YouTube many content creators are using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; a service that allows people to pay their favorite channels either per video or per month, in exchange the user can get extra perks ranging from getting the videos a week early which is very common to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/gradeaundera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;having the YouTuber’s phone number so you can call them&lt;/a&gt;. Many big YouTube channels use it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/scishow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SciShow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/veritasium&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Veritasium&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/Kurzgesagt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In a Nutshell – Kurzgesagt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ThreatWire&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Threat Wire (by Hak5)&lt;/a&gt; and loads more. It allows niche fanbases to support their content creators and does work out very well for some channels that use it, it tends to work best for channels where the content creator and the content viewer have a connection and does not work well for channels that are disconnected from their fan base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this being the replacement to advertising is it would be the only form of monetization available, this form of monetization is not as good for channels that are disconnected from their fanbase and does not work well for channels that don’t have fanbases. Although some channels don’t have fans that does not mean they should not exist or monetize their content, helpful videos showing how to fix your specific laptop are brilliant however you would not subscribe to the channel as only that video is relevant for you and other ones would not be, the main point is not all content can be monetized in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Paywall&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other option is to paywall the content for example sites like Netflix, Hulu, Amazon Instant Video, and iTunes. This option it not ideal as people would be paying a considerable amount when you add up all the websites you use from news and sports to blogs and small websites. Paywalls are only good currently for media we are used to paying for like TV, Movies and Music. Nearly all websites can’t work with paywalls as it would be hard to get customers without advertising… and without online advertisements the only option would be costly TV ads. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/failed-paywalls-2010-4/the-new-york-times-times-select-1?IR=T&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Many websites like newspapers and magazines fail when they implement paywalls&lt;/a&gt;, from big papers like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-newscorp-sun-paywall-idUSKCN0SO25R20151030&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Sun&lt;/a&gt; to small papers like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestar.com/news/gta/2015/03/07/note-to-readers-star-to-end-paid-digital-subscriptions-on-april-1.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toronto Star&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online advertisements may be the only viable way for many websites to monetize their content, and as I discussed in &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The Ethics of Adblock”&lt;/a&gt; Adblock is rising to the point where it could be a big problem to the internet. I would like to know of any other ways we could have an advertisement free internet so if you have any ideas message me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_AceLewis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/_AceLewis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; or leave a comment on this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 21:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/blog/alternative-to-ads</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/blog/alternative-to-ads</guid>
        
        <category>adverts</category>
        
        <category>adblock</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Image Formats and When to Use Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a few image formats used on the web, this blog post is aims the explain what each one is in simple terms and also explain the situations where each format is appropriate. Some people argue over what image format people should use (all the time) however it is much better to understand the situations where specific image formats should and shouldn’t be used and the situations where people abuse formats.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-basics&quot;&gt;The Basics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most images you see are Raster images (sometimes confusingly called bitmaps) they are made up of many pixels, each pixel has a colour that is displayed on the screen. The colours of each pixel is saved in a colour space it is not really important to know exactly what colour space is being used but you should know that all colours you see are reproduced with only three numbers. These three numbers represent different quantities e.g. Red, Green and Blue, or Hue, Saturation and Value, if transparency is needed the image then there would be an extra number often referred to as Alpha. What most image formats aim to do is get the best quality image using the smallest amount of bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-main-image-formats&quot;&gt;The Main Image Formats&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main formats I am going to cover are BMP, PNG, JPEG, GIF and GIFV. These are all raster graphic formats, I will also cover SVG a vector graphic format. I will also try to compare the different formats to show you when certain formats should and shouldn’t be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bitmap-bmp&quot;&gt;Bitmap (BMP)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clear any ambiguity as Raster images are sometimes referred to as bitmap images I am talking about the BMP file format. A bitmap is the simplest image format available it stores the colour value of each pixel with an optional transparency layer. BMPs often don’t use transparency so only use RGB (Red, Green and Blue) to store colours, images can be compressed but often are not and the file has the size of the image and the colour at each pixel. As the image is not compressed it is very simple to process and is a lossless image format meaning that by saving an image in this format no quality is lost at all however the file sizes are very large so it is almost never used to store images or distribute them on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;portable-network-graphics-png&quot;&gt;Portable Network Graphics (PNG)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portable Network Graphics also known as PNG is a lossless image format like BMPs however they are compressed. The compression applied to PNGs don’t change the data so therefore don’t change the image, it is similar to zipping and unzipping a file. One other way to compress PNGs before the comressiong algorithms are applied is by using indexed colour. Indexed colour means that it makes a big list of all the colours in an image and then when each colour in the list is used in an image it puts the location of the pixel in the list, as the colours in the list are made up of three numbers and only one number is needed to point to the location in the list you save on the amount of data needed to store the image. The size of the list and therefore the maximum size of the number used to point at the list is dependant on the number of colours in the image, you can reduce the file size even further by approximating the colours used and making the list smaller however this leads to lossy compression, this compression may be lossy however if you compare two images the difference is hard to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To compare PNG compression to BMP I got a lossless PNG of Tux (the Linux kernel mascot) and then saved the image as a BPM (without transparency), the BMP image was 561 KB. The lossless PNG is 40.2 KB only 7.2% of the BPM showing that the PNG format can compress a raw image by a considerable amount. To compare the lossy against lossless PNGs I compressed the image of Tux using indexed colour and the final image was 17.9 KB that is only 44.5% of the lossless image, in the lossy image you can notice banding in the forehead of the penguin however this not that noticeable and would be perfect for a website as it saves a lot of bandwidth and speeds up the page load time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title-half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tux PNG lossless (40.2 KB)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tux PNG lossy (17.9 KB)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container-half&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Tux Lossless&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/tux.png&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Tux Lossy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/tux-min.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create indexed PNGs using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pngquant.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pngquant&lt;/a&gt; (Free and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pornel/pngquant&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;opensource&lt;/a&gt;) however if you don’t want to install that software to check it out you could use online services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinypng.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TinyPNG&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://compresspng.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CompressPNG&lt;/a&gt;. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://compresspng.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CompressPNG&lt;/a&gt; more as it easily allows you to manually tweak with the numbers of colours used in the indexing list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: Animated PNGs have existed since 2008 however browser support is lacking, &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=apng&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;only Firefox and Safari 18% of the global browsers support animated PNGs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jpeg&quot;&gt;JPEG&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPEG is the most commonly used image format on the internet, it can be used as lossless compression however it is mostly used for lossy compression. The idea behind it is the lost data is not that important for the image and the image will be perceptually lossless. As data is being lost it can compress images much more than PNGs however not in all circumstances, also a big downfall of JPEG is it does not support transparency at all unlike PNG. JPEG compression initially works by splitting the file up into many blocks of pixels usually 8 by 8, it then performs discrete cosine transforms (turns the image into waves) on the blocks of pixels and to compression is done by setting the smaller less needed numbers from the discrete cosine transform to zero (removing the small waves that don’t contribute much) so the data is compressed considerably when Huffman encoding is applied. JPEG compression is bad for text as the straight lines get “fuzzy”, also successive compression of a JPEG image deteriorate the quality considerably this is bad and is why some people dislike JPEG. Saving a JPEG using exactly the same compression as originally used does not reduce the quality as much (if at all) however when images are shared on the internet one image may be compressed by JPEG many times using all different compression tables (in the discrete cosine transforms) so images have blocky artifacts near edges, an example image is shown below of the text of an image that has been posted and reposted online. The fuzziness around the text is caused by this successive JPEG compression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/JPEG-text-comression.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JPEG text&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big problem for JPEG and is one reason why people dislike it, the image that has been compressed many times is probably bigger than the image after the first compression as the fuzziness is now part of the data the image is trying to compress. Also for text it could be much smaller if a indexed colour PNG is used as not that many colour would be present so it would be lossless and have a smaller file size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comparison of JPEG compression against PNG is shown below on the image of Tux, the PNG is slightly larger however it does also have a transparency layer unlike the JPEG. As you can see in the image the lossy PNG has a much better image quality, around sharp edges there are artifacts in the JPEG image along with the features being smoothed out unlike in the PNG. The JPEG compression problems is more apparent when you zoom in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title-half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tux lossy PNG (17.9 KB)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tux lossy JPEG (15.4 KB)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container-half&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Tux lossy PNG&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/tux-min.png&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Tux lossy JPEG&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/tux-min.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title-half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tux lossy PNG eye zoomed in&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tux lossy JPEG eye zoomed in&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container-half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Tux lossy PNG eye&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/tux-min-eye-png.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Tux lossy JPEG eye&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/tux-min-eye-jpg.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This highlights the problems with JPEG however it does so unfairly…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JPEG is an acronym for Joint Photographic Experts Group, and as the name implies this compression format was made for the use with photographs of the real world not images of penguins made on a computer. JPEG compression excels in the compression of photographs and if the compression algorithm is applied only once the compressed image is almost indistinguishable from the initial picture. As JPEG is brilliant at compression photographs nearly all cameras save the images in this format meaning that it is difficult to get a raw photographic image that was initially save in a lossless format e.g. PNG. High end cameras can take images in “raw” however the final images are almost always distributed in JPEG format and the appeal to “shoot raw” is due to more control of the colour and exposure when editing the photograph afterwards. Photographs will tend to have much more than 256 colours so indexed PNGs can not be used, this is the main reason why images shared online tend to be in this format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gif&quot;&gt;GIF&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GIF is an image format often used to share short moving images (without sound), most people online have seen GIFs used to show clips of cats or people falling over but that was not what they were intended for and it not how they should be used. GIFs don’t need to be moving images they just are images that similar to indexed PNGs they can only have 256 colours in the image, they then are compressed by a compression algorithm called Lempel–Ziv–Welch. Lempel–Ziv–Welch is a lossless compression algorithm however images will look bad as only 256 colours can be used so and images themselves are not losslessly compressed. Lempel–Ziv–Welch is not as good as DEFLATE the compression algorithm used by PNG so an indexed PNG would have a smaller file size, despite this GIFs have one big benefit over PNGs and JPEGs they can have moving images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/wow.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Wow GIF&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why GIFs are still used is only because they allow the looping of moving images, it was initially intended for “cool” embedded email icons that you could embed into your HTML only website in the 1990’s. The “Wow GIF” shown above would not look professional or even be used on any website now but if you can find old usually academic websites that do use GIFs in the way that they were intended e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jila.colorado.edu/~ajsh/insidebh/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Now GIFs are used to display videos with no sound however it is a really bad thing as each frame of the gif is a raw image so GIF videos tend to have huge file sizes and are often very slow to load. To reduce the file size GIFs tend to have a low frame rate, the bad image quality and blurred frames of a GIFs is shown below. (I don’t want to embed a large GIF so you can see the GIF &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/q61ve2F.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on imgur.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/gif.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bad GIF&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bonus fact, GIFs don’t need to loop they can be made to play just once however they are almost always used with the looping ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gifv&quot;&gt;GIFV&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GIFVs are the “solution” to the GIF problem, they have much smaller file sizes and therefore load much faster than traditional GIFs. GIFVs are just autoplaying and autolooping MP4 videos without audio and all video features like the pause, play, and the timeline removed. One big problem for GIFVs is they can’t be embedded on a webpage in the same way on all devices, phones, tablets and many mobile devices however the image quality is much better and colors that can be used is much more than 256. Videos are much more efficient than showing individual pictures one after the other like in GIFs as they can use more complex compression that can rely on the frames easier in the video. (I don’t want to branch out too much on that topic) GIFVs are great and solve the problems of GIFs, one slight benefit of GIFs is they require less computation to display as there is no compression however this is not an issue as I am not aware of a device that can connect to the internet and has the computational power to display GIFs but not videos, also the power used to download the GIF far out ways and power saved by the less complex computation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;svg&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally SVGs, all the other image types mentioned before are Raster image formats that store pixels in different ways SVGs are totally different. SVGs are the most used format Vector graphics, instead of storing the pixel values Vector graphics store instructions on how to make the image, for example place a circle here I want it this big and it needs to be blue. These instructions are then read by the browser or file viewer and the image is displayed. As SVGs are just instructions the files they produce can be very small when compared to PNGs or JPEGs. SVG stands for Scalable Vector Graphics and as the name implies the images produced are scalable meaning that you can zoom in or enlarge a SVG without causing and problems, the same SVG that is used for an icon on a website can be used and put on a giant billboard. If you took a PNG or JPEG image from a webpage and scaled it up to the size of a billboard it would look terrible as the pixels would be large enough to see however SVGs have no pixels only shapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SVGs are not only used for logos but are nearly always used for fonts, SVGs are perfect as they can be scaled to any size without loosing quality. Fonts are not limited to words and text either on this block the share buttons (Facebook, Reddit, ect.) are all fonts from &lt;a href=&quot;http://fontawesome.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt; not images so they have the benefit of not changing when people view the webpage on different devices. An example of what would happen to raster text when scaled up is shown below;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/image-types/Bitmap_VS_SVG.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Raster vs Vector&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A extra feature of SVGs that is very underused is animations, complex 3D animations can be made however they are often not used as it is hard to embed them on webpages (you need to embed them on the page) one of this in use is &lt;a href=&quot;http://debeissat.nicolas.free.fr/images_svg/ball_3d.svg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a spinning ball&lt;/a&gt;. The downside of SVGs is some very old browsers don’t support them, for example IE8 and before. In that case you can have a PNG or JPEG as a fallback to load for those people. Vector graphics are used in many online map websites like Google maps, the roads (not in satellite view) are SVGs as you can zoom in, not much data is needed to draw a road and they display correctly on many devices that support SVG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion for this blog post is that JPEG is good for photographic images however repeated application of JPEG compression severely damages images, PNGs are a good lossless format and can be used in a lossy format to compress non photographic images better than JPEG. GIFs are not used for the purpose they are intended for so GIFVs (basically renamed MP4s) can in most cases be used to replace them. I also stated that SVGs are very good but only for their specific applications in fonts, maps and icons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/blog/image-formats-and-when-to-use-them</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/blog/image-formats-and-when-to-use-them</guid>
        
        <category>images</category>
        
        <category>formats</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: This website</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-website&quot;&gt;This Website&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is a small project I am doing, it is made using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; a static website builder, the website is made using HTML, CSS and JavaScript however by using Jekyll you don’t need to write all the HTML for example once you have made the footer you can just include it in any page by writing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;footer.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, you can also use for loops and conditional statements in the HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image below shows the Jekyll code used to make the footer;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/thiswebsite/footer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Image of my footer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also once the HTML, CSS and JavaScript have been made the content e.g. this post, can be made in Markdown a simple markup language the same markup used in the Reddit comment system, most Github READMEs and often throughout the internet. By using Markdown it makes it simple to publish pages as if you need to change any HTML on all webpages e.g. the footer you easily can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/project/this-website</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/project/this-website</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: The Ethics of Adblock</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adblock&lt;/b&gt; is software used on computers and mobile devices whose main purpose is to block web advertisements. Adblock is growing in it’s use and an estimated &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pagefair.com/2015/ad-blocking-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;20.3% of people in the UK use it&lt;/a&gt;. Mobile phones have for a long time been a safe haven for online advertisements as installing Adblock meant either changing to a specialised browser or by Jailbreaking/Rooting the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-do-people-use-it&quot;&gt;Why do People Use it?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why someone would choose to install Adblock, one is they don’t want to be tracked by online advertisers although by Adblocking extensions do not necessarily try to stop tracking it can be enabled in some software. This is a good reason to use Adblock is a good one as trackers ignore your “Do Not Track” if you have enabled it in your browser and will track you anyway, web tracking can bypass this blocking by tracking the browsers “fingerprint” which includes the IP address, screen size and resolution, browser, operating system, installed extensions and other features, so although people don’t want to be tracked they can be however Adblock can stop a lot of tracking that is done by third parties. First parties will still be able to track you for example Facebook whilst you are on Facebook but you can diable Facebook from knowing what sites you visit that have the like on Facebook button. Another reason to use Adblock is virus’ can be distributed through them, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-05-14/self-regulation-fails-to-curb-web-ad-abuses-panel-says&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yahoo and YouTube&lt;/a&gt; have distributed ads and malware. It is not uncommon to see, one example of this I have observed on a YouTube video is shown here;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock/free-minecraft.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;&amp;quot;Free&amp;quot; Minecraft advert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously this is not real however I wanted to check to see exactly what is was, on the install page if you scroll to the bottom you can see that the website does disclose that the software you are installing for your copy of Minecraft is adware (software that injects advert into your webpages) however many people would not read this and younger people (who this advert is aimed at) would install without reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock/adware-notice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Test showing that it is adware&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then installed the software on a Virtual Machine and as expected it installed adware and did not give you a copy of Minecraft as promised. Google, Yahoo and other advertising networks should monitor that adverts they publish on their ad networks and should have more accountability for what they allow. This is a serious reason to install Adblock especially on the computers of older people and children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason people seem to use Adblock is because of annoying adverts, some adverts are flashy, some autoplay videos when you are trying to view a news article and advertisements seem to get more annoying as time goes on. Annoying advertisements have existed in the past e.g popups however most browsers today have popup blockers to block this annoying type of advertising. Now annoying adverts take many forms not just popups. The reason why websites like newspapers are allowing more annoying adverts is because they tend to pay more per view however this short term strategy may hurt the industry as it forces users to install Adblocking software. I believe if all websites used less annoying adverts people would be less inclined to use and install Adblock, however the short term benefits of allowing annoying adverts is favored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-mobile-safe-haven&quot;&gt;The Mobile Safe Haven&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently mobile phones and tablets tend to not have Adblock installed only about &lt;a href=&quot;http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/2015_report-the_cost_of_ad_blocking.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2% of users on IOS and android have Adblock installed&lt;/a&gt;. This has the potential to be a good thing however many websites exploit this by showing annoying adverts as they know their users can’t block the ads without Rooting or Jailbreaking, as a result users will then want to install Adblock on mobile devices. The image shown below contains two examples or annoying adverts on mobile, one that autoplayed a video and the other a full screen advert that you had to click a little &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; in the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock/phone-adverts-50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Annoying mobile adverts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of advertising would not be acceptable on desktop and it is not acceptable on mobile, however at the moment mobile phones and tablets don’t have large Adblock percentages due to the difficulty of installing Adblock it will soon to become easy. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/releasenotes/General/WhatsNewInSafari/Articles/Safari_9.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In IO9 Apple introduced content filters&lt;/a&gt;, although Apple didn’t state they were for blocking adverts that is what they are intended for and are the main purpose they are being used for e.g &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/safari-blocker/id1011678834?ls=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Refine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1025729002&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1Blocker&lt;/a&gt; and many pretty much all content filters. Fairly recently Adblock Plus introduced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://adblockplus.org/android-install&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adblock Browser&lt;/a&gt; for Android, simply Firefox with Adblocking filters to block the annoying mobile adverts. As both these methods make installing Adblock easy on mobile devices without Jailbreaking or Rooting combined with adverts on mobile being more annoying than desktop I suspect that the Adblock percentages for mobile phones and tablets will sky rocket and will not take that long for the percentages to be comparable to desktop. Unless anything is done to solve the underlying problems mobile will not be a safe haven anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-prevalence-and-effect-of-adblock&quot;&gt;The Prevalence and Effect of Adblock&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adblock seems like a good solution to improve your browsing experience however it has a very big drawback, the reason websites show ads is to make money to pay for hosting, domain names, and the labor of writing the articles. By blocking adverts you no longer fund the websites you visit with your eyes, now this would not have a large impact on the websites revenue however the amount of users that have Adblock in the UK &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pagefair.com/2015/ad-blocking-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;grew by 81% this year to 20.3%&lt;/a&gt; if this trend continues most people will use Adblock so websites will have to find other ways to monetize their content mainly by using paywalls. 20.3% is a considerable amount however for people aged &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/09/21/apple-adblock-stats/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;18-29 the amount of Adblocking users is 41%&lt;/a&gt;, as a result &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pagefair.com/2015/ad-blocking-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tech and gaming websites see a much higher percentage of Adblock users&lt;/a&gt;. Adblock cost the industry about &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pagefair.com/2015/ad-blocking-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;21.8 billion dollars in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, this figure is expected to grow to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pagefair.com/2015/ad-blocking-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;41.4 billion dollars in 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally media has been free to consume online however as more and more people use Adblock paywalls will be introduced, YouTube has been a website that all content was free to consume however a big announcement this year was the introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/red&quot;&gt;YouTube Red&lt;/a&gt; whereby users could pay a monthly fee to remove advertisements and access paywalled original content. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adweek.com/socialtimes/pewdiepie-on-youtube-red-adblock-has-actual-consequences/629327&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“YouTube Red exist because using Adblock has actual consequences”&lt;/a&gt;, other websites will follow in YouTube footsteps and internet users will end up less and less content that can be viewed freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-ads-are-evolving&quot;&gt;The Ads are Evolving&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although one way to bypass Adblock is to paywall your content a lot of publishers are moving towards “Sponsored Content”, as mentioned before YouTube is introducing paywalls as one way to tackle Adblock however many of the publishers on YouTube have sponsors, if you watch YouTube videos I am sure you have heard of Audible, Harry’s Razors, Lynda.com and many more companies that sponsor the videos. These sponsors can pay a flat rate per video but often pay the content maker a referral from the users that either use the link in the description or a coupon code. This type of advertising can’t be blocked and is becoming more and more common, some big YouTubers will make whole videos that are sponsored for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ldMknYJboU8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FPSRussia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LoaEy7CCC1E&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DudePerfect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One big problem with Sponsored videos is that quite often the video does not at all state anywhere within it and often not in the description that the video is sponsored, not only is this very dishonest and misleading but it is also against advertising rules and regulations. The “Oreo Lick Race” was a sponsored advertising campaign to advertise Oreos by getting many famous YouTube stars to participate, as part of the deal they did not disclose that they were making sponsored videos. Some of the YouTubers evolved in this were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/TomSka&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thomas “TomSka” Ridgewell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L11vobQmxx0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[Video mirror]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dan_and_Phil&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dan and Phil&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/NiallAndThe4OtherPotatoes/videos/440983762721516/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[Video mirror]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCebpq6lNn_oV_Y2XiRzR3Vg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emma Blackery&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/NiallAndThe4OtherPotatoes/videos/440983762721516/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[video not available but proof it was posted]&lt;/a&gt;. These videos were serious violations of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asa.org.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Advertising Standards Authority&lt;/a&gt; because the videos were not &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/media/2014/nov/26/youtube-ad-oreo-banned-advertising-lick-race&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“obviously identifiable marketing communications”&lt;/a&gt; they were therefore removed from YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a one off event and is becoming more common even though &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/154235&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube have now revised their policies on paid product endorsement&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-34138251&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Microsoft paid YouTubers upto £20,000 to advertise the Xbox One as part of a ““deceptive” ad campaign” under similar circumstances with a non disclosure agreement&lt;/a&gt;. Sponsored videos are often not disclosed and sometimes hard to detect a prime example is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w9DH6yR44q8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this advert for fashion items&lt;/a&gt;. There should be much more pressure on YouTubers to comply with advertising rules to curve this trend and have a more transparent web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of this has been aimed as YouTube however this can be seen all across the web, South Park has done episodes on how adverts on news websites display misleading advertisements, South Park has also made a few episodes with the plot of how advertising companies are trying to advertise to people whilst disguising the ads as normal content, this would not be joked about on such a big show unless it is very apparent to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-war-on-adblock&quot;&gt;The War on Adblock&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adverts are evolving to bypass Adblock as shown above however as more and more people use it and it becomes even more of a problem there will be an online battle of publishers vs Adblock. Many Adblock users think that there will always be a way to block ads that may not be true, the reason why ads can easily be blocked is because of filters. Adblock filters for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EasyList&lt;/a&gt; contain a large list of rules, these rules are then applied when you load a website. The rules aim to block ads but keep the real content, this is currently very effective as most adverts are served through networks like Google Adsense so it is easy to see what is an advert and what is not in the future Google may allow publishers to display adverts through their own domain making it much harder to block the adverts. Another method to stop the use of Adblock is detect if the user is running Adblock and then either display a message asking the user to turn off Adblock and allow them to view the content or block the user from seeing the content all together. This method is easy to implement and can become harder for Adblockers to bypass, there has already been some minor battles with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sitexw/FuckAdBlock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FuckAdblock&lt;/a&gt; a script that you can easily put into your website that detects Adblocking users so you can display messages or block them from viewing content and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Mechazawa/FuckFuckAdblock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FuckFuckAdblock&lt;/a&gt; a Userscript to stop &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sitexw/FuckAdBlock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FuckAdblock&lt;/a&gt; from detecting if Adblock is being used. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sitexw/FuckAdBlock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FuckAdblock&lt;/a&gt; and many other anti-adblock measures today rely on JavaScript so the detecting of Adblock is done on the client side so can be theoretically blocked however in the future Adblock could be detected on the server side by seeing if your browser loads a embedded image or not, this would then be impossible to bypass with the current Adblock extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-opinions-and-conclusion&quot;&gt;My Opinions and Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that adverts fund websites so blocking them is bad however the advertising industry is shooting themselves in the foot by displaying annoying adverts forcing users to install Adblock. As the percentage of Adblock users rises websites will just put their content behind paywalls so users can’t freely view them or use more sophisticated ways to detect Adblock and only allow non-adblock users to view them. I believe that Adblock is an overkill solution, people are annoyed by obnoxious ads and install Adblock but that blocks all ads even the ones they didn’t mind. From what I have seen online many people feel entitled to view free content without ads but don’t say how publishers should make the money without charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a happy medium one where websites can monetize their content and users can freely view the content without being annoyed by ads. Also some ads can be good for the users, they can find products websites or services that they enjoy for example the YouTube adverts for Harrys razors have influenced me into looking into finding cheaper and better razors and not buy the massively marked up razors (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisismoney.co.uk/money/bills/article-1677114/Great-razor-rip-off-Gillettes-4750-mark-up.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;over 4,000% markup&lt;/a&gt;) in the supermarkets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested to know what your opinions of Adblock are and what would you deem to be acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 22:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/blog/the-ethics-of-adblock</guid>
        
        <category>adblock</category>
        
        <category>ethics</category>
        
        <category>adverts</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Spintax</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;spintax&quot;&gt;Spintax&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a Python module that parses Spintax. Spintax also known as spinning syntax is often used then text is “spun”, all this means is that the code can create many sentences or paragraphs that are all worded differently however all mean the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;simple-example&quot;&gt;Simple example:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;{Hey|Hello|Hi} {this|here} is {an example of|how to use} Spintax{.|!|}&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;can-produce&quot;&gt;Can produce:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hey this is an example of Spintax.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hi here is how to use Spintax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello this how to use Spintax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hi here is an example of Spintax!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above example Spintax can return 36 possibilities however this number grows exponentially as more spintax is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code was originally made so the bots I code can respond with automated responses that are unique, I found that by doing this people tended to interact with the bot more. I also noticed that by displaying the same information different ways to people who had trouble understanding English (as it was not their native language) were more likely to understand the meaning of the sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many applications of Spintax from generating &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AceLewis/spintax/blob/master/examples/simple_password_generator.py&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;memorable passwords&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AceLewis/spintax/blob/master/examples/super_hero_name_generator.py&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;usernames&lt;/a&gt; to making automated responses seem less robotic. Spintax is also often used for small local newspapers and news stations, instead of employing someone to write articles on specialised topics such as the current economy or other national things covered they outsource the writing to a company e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eurekalert.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eurekalert&lt;/a&gt; that will write a good article once using Spintax and then distribute many spun articles to their customers. This is often not noticed as most people only get one local newspaper, however this does create similar content and has been pointed out by many people including &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/44ojS4UNn8I?t=16s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Conan O’Brien&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This module is simple to use;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;import spintax
string = r&quot;{Hey|Hello|Hi} {this|here} is {an example of|how to use} Spintax{.|!|}&quot;
print(spintax.parse(string))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just input the string into the parse function and it will return the spun text, unlike other Spintax parsers this parser is allows the user to escape the syntax characters for example;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;spintax.parse(r&quot;\{example|shown|here}&quot;)
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; [&#39;{example|shown|here}&#39;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download this module either download a copy from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AceLewis/Spintax&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and install manually or use pip,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install spintax
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/project/Spintax</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/project/Spintax</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Steam Trading Bot</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;steam-trading-bot&quot;&gt;Steam Trading Bot&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt; is a gaming platform used by &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/stats/&quot;&gt;millions of people a day&lt;/a&gt;, users on this platform can trade items such as Trading cards, emoticons, and in game items with other people. The bot I made was able to trade all these items and was able to add and remove friends and chat with automated responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tips-and-advice&quot;&gt;Tips and Advice&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my tips and advice for people that want to make their own Steam trading Bots firstly the language to choose, the two main options are C# or Node.js. For C# the main library you will use is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Jessecar96/SteamBot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SteamBot&lt;/a&gt;
I originally coded my first trading bot in C# and it was okay as there is lots of good documentation however I chose at the time to use Node.js as it had libraries to deal with trade offers and the C# libraries only could deal with trade requests (the older trading system). The C# libraries now fully support trade offers however I still believe that Node.js is the best language to choose for the following reasons, firstly the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/SteamBot/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SteamBot subreddit&lt;/a&gt; made to to help people with issues related to the C# library often recommends Node.js now especially for new people, Node.js does not need to me compiled all you need is Node.js installed on your PC and a text editor, a big issue with C# is to run on Linux operating systems Mono has to be used this can cause many problems with different versions doing slightly different things, Mono and C# is slower than Node.js, and finally Node.js uses a lot less RAM and CPU than the C# libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now assuming you are using Node.js you have many libraries to choose from including &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steamcommunity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steamcommunity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steam-tradeoffer-manager&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-tradeoffer-manager&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steam-user&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-user&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seishun/node-steam&quot;&gt;node-steam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seishun/node-steam-trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-trade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Alex7Kom/node-steam-tradeoffers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-tradeoffers&lt;/a&gt;, and much more however in my opinion the best libraries to use are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steamcommunity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steamcommunity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steam-tradeoffer-manager&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-tradeoffer-manager&lt;/a&gt; as only these two are needed to make a trading bot and you don’t need to have a Steam API key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/SteamBot/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SteamBot subreddit&lt;/a&gt; is good for simple questions regarding Steams API and other things but do your own research before posting as most problems can be fixed with the help of Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steam often goes down, sometimes just the API and sometimes more than just that it is annoying whilst testing to fond out that the reason your bot is not connecting is because Steam is down, so if you want to check use &lt;a href=&quot;https://steamstat.us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steam Status&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-end-of-this-bot&quot;&gt;The End of This Bot&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bot started trading in February and little maintenance was needed however on December the 9th 2015 Steam introduced &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/mobile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steam mobile&lt;/a&gt; as a mandatory two factor authentication needed for instant trades. If a user did not set up Steam mobile trades will be held in escrow for 3 days as other users needed this feature the bot was broken thus forcing me to recode it. This bot used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seishun/node-steam&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Alex7Kom/node-steam-tradeoffers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-tradeoffers&lt;/a&gt; libraries however the new bot uses different libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-bots-life&quot;&gt;The Bots Life&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 10 months the bot was operational it made over 30,000 trades to thousands of users, as the bot was set up mainly for a hobby I think that this was a success. It was very interesting and fun project, the intention of the project was not to make a profit however about £200-250 was made in the months it was running. The bot ran on a Raspberry Pi so the electric costs were negligible, and it needed no effort to run and would only be checked upon about once a fortnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-next-trading-bot&quot;&gt;The Next Trading Bot&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously this bot no longer works however small parts of it were used in the updated bot, the new bots code uses the libraries &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steamcommunity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steamcommunity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DoctorMcKay/node-steam-tradeoffer-manager&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;node-steam-tradeoffer-manager&lt;/a&gt; the reason for this was because &lt;a href=&quot;https://backpack.tf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;backpack.tf&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/srabouin/backpack.tf-automatic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Automatic&lt;/a&gt; uses these libraries and if any other big changes in Steam were made in logging in and/or the trading it would be much easier to update the bot as I can just make the same changes as they do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/project/steam-trading-bot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/project/steam-trading-bot</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Question: Why did the Chicken cross the road?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To get to the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 17:54:46 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://acelewis.com/question/your-project-name</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acelewis.com/question/your-project-name</guid>
        
        
        <category>question</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
